<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cloud on Clouds&amp;Docker</title>
    <link>http://todzhang.com/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cloud on Clouds&amp;Docker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://todzhang.com/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS certification</title>
      <link>http://todzhang.com/posts/2019-08-25-aws-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://todzhang.com/posts/2019-08-25-aws-certificate/</guid>
      <description>Concepting Cloud computing is the on-demand delivery of IT resources and applications via the Internet with pay-as-you-go pricing. Whether you run applications that share photos to millions of mobile users or deliver services that support the critical operations of your business, the cloud provides rapid access to flexible and low-cost IT resources.
In its simplest form, cloud computing provides an easy way to access servers, storage, databases, and a broad set of application services over the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cloud computering</title>
      <link>http://todzhang.com/posts/2017-12-18-clouding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://todzhang.com/posts/2017-12-18-clouding/</guid>
      <description>Concepts Cloud computing is the on-demand demand delivery of compute database storage applications and other IT resources through a cloud services platform via the Internet with pay-as-you-go pricing.
The 6 advantages of cloud computering Trade Capital Expense For Variable Expense Benefit from massive economies of scale Stop guessing about capacity Increase speed and agility Stop spending money running and maintaining data centers Go global in minutes 3 types of cloud computing  IAAS PAAS SAAS  &amp;ldquo;Certification is the beginning of your journey, not the end&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cloud computering</title>
      <link>http://todzhang.com/posts/2017-12-18-openstack-vs-openshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://todzhang.com/posts/2017-12-18-openstack-vs-openshift/</guid>
      <description>openshift vs openstack The shoft and direct answer is `OpenShift Origin can run on top of OpenStack. They are complementary projects that work well together. OpenShift Origin is not presently part of OpenStack, and does not compete with OpenStack. If you stand up your own OpenStack system, you can make it even more useful by installing OpenShift Origin on top of it.&amp;rsquo;
OpenStack is IAAS OpenStack provides “Infrastructure-as-a-Service”, or “IaaS”. It provides bootable virtual machines, networking, block storage, object storage, and so forth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Openshift tips</title>
      <link>http://todzhang.com/posts/2017-11-29-openshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://todzhang.com/posts/2017-11-29-openshift/</guid>
      <description>Commands bible install cli in Mac brew install openshift-cli Frequently used commands Start mini shift minishift start OC commands oc config view Start a new application oc new-app https://github.com/openshift/nodejs-ex -l name=toddapp To switch project oc project Show a high level overview of the current project oc status # Export the overview of the current project in an svg file. oc status -o dot | dot -T svg -o project.svg # See an overview of the current project including details for any identified issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>